The question is, if you get a cloth dripping wet without gravity and you ring it out, what's
going to happen?
What will happen to a wrung out cloth?
So, and had to use equipment that was here on board the space station.
We might have the coolest washcloths ever here on the space station.
I'm going to show you.
This is one of our washcloths.
And it's packed in.
It's put down into this little tiny hockey puck so that it saves space.
When you open up a hockey puck and you pull out your washcloth, this is the one I'm going
to use for the experiment today.
And so when you open up your hockey puck and turn it into a washcloth, it was compressed
in a great big vice somewhere.
Okay, so here's my washcloth, like a magic trick.
And now I'm going to get this soaking wet and then we're going to see what will happen
when we wring it out.
Meredith and Kendra suggested that I dip this in a bag, but bags don't hold water in
space.
So instead, I filled a water bag.
This has drinking water in it.
And I'm going to squirt a bunch of water into this washcloth.
Okay, so here's a soaking wet washcloth.
Get the microphones.
You can hear me while I'm talking.
And now let's start wringing it out.
It's really wet.
Let's be coming up to the water.
The water is all over my hands.
In fact, it rings out of the cloth into my hands.
And if I let go of the cloth carefully, the water sort of has it stick to my hand.
Okay, so the experiment worked beautifully.
And the answer to the question is the water squeezes out of the cloth.
And then because of the surface tension of the water, it actually runs along the surface
of the cloth and then up into my hand, almost like you had jello on your hands or gel on
your hand.
And it'll just stay there.
Wonderful moisturizer on my hands.
And the cloth doesn't really unravel itself.
It just stays there floating like a dog's chew toy, soaking wet.
Great experiment, worked perfectly.
Meredith and Kendra, congratulations.
Great idea.